Finding Aid for Daughters of the American Revolution, Fort Pontchartrain-Elizabeth Cass Chapter Records, 1916-2001.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Daughters of the American Revolution, Fort Pontchartrain-Elizabeth Cass Chapter (Grosse Pointe Farms, Mich.) Records, 1916-2001
Daughters of the American Revolution. Fort Pontchartrain-Elizabeth Cass Chapter (Grosse Pointe Farms, Mich.)
5 linear feet, 2 oversized volumes and 1 oversize folder
0520 Be.1 2; Be.1 Outsize
The Fort Pontchartrain Chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution (DAR) was authorized on February 7, 1916 in Highland Park, Michigan with Mrs. Ward Garett as organizing secretary. The Elizabeth Cass Chapter was organized in 1942 in Grosse Pointe Farms. Because of diminishing membership, the two chapters merged in 1990, becoming the Fort Pontchartrain-Elizabeth Cass Chapter.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were transferred to the Bentley Historical Library by the DAR state regent in 2004. Donor no. 1171 )
The record group is open to research.
The Fort Pontchartrain Chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution (DAR) was authorized on February 7, 1916 in Highland Park, Michigan with Mrs. Ward Garett as organizing secretary. The Elizabeth Cass Chapter was organized in 1942 in Grosse Pointe Farms. Because of diminishing membership, the two chapters merged in 1990, becoming the Fort Pontchartrain-Elizabeth Cass Chapter.
The record group is divided into three series: Fort Pontchartrain Chapter, 1916-1990; Elizabeth Cass Chapter, 1942-1990; and the Fort Pontchartrain-Elizabeth Cass Chapter.. Fort Pontchartrain Chapter records include minutes, applications, regent reports, history, by-laws, charter, chapter history and other materials relating to its activities. Elizabeth Cass Chapter records include minutes, applications, by-laws, correspondence, clippings, genealogy, and a photograph of a portrait of Elizabeth Cass. Fort Pontchartrain-Elizabeth Cass Chapter includes minutes, applications, and other records of the combined chapter.
Subjects:
Daughters of the American Revolution. Fort Pontchartrain-Elizabeth Cass Chapter (Grosse Pointe Farms, Mich.); Daughters of the American Revolution. Fort Pontchartrain Chapter (Highland Park, Mich.); Daughters of the American Revolution. Elizabeth Cass Chapter (Grosse Pointe Farms, Mich.); Patriotic societies--Michigan--Grosse Pointe Farms.; Patriotic societies--Michigan--Highland Park.; Women--Michigan--Grosse Pointe Farms--Societies and clubs.; Women--Michigan--Highland Park--Societies and clubs.
Contributors:
Daughters of the American Revolution. Fort Pontchartrain Chapter (Highland Park, Mich.); Daughters of the American Revolution. Elizabeth Cass Chapter (Grosse Pointe Farms, Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Fort Pontchartrain Chapter, 1916-1990
  - Minutes, 1916-1990
    - 1916-1947, 8 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1947-1964, 5 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1965-1990, 7 folders (Box 2)
  - Applications
    - Nos. 1-599, 4 volumes (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (1 folder) (Box 3)
  - Regents Reports, 1920-1964, 2 volumes (Box 3)
  - History/Miscellaneous
    - By-Laws, 1956 (Box 4)
    - Charter, 1916, 1 oversize folder (Box 4)
    - Fort Pontchartrain Chapter History, 1916-1932
      - 1916-1937, 1 binder (Box 4)
      - 1936-1957, 1 folder (Box 4)
      - Genealogy, Allen Family (Box 4)
      - Golden Anniversary, 1966 (Box 4)
      - Guest Books, 3 volumes (Box 4)
      - Membership (Box 4)
      - Realia (Box 4)
      - Excellence in History, DAR award medal (Box 4)
      - Gavel and printing die with official seal (Box 4)
        (see p.14, Fort Pontchartrain Chapter History for history of gavel)
      - Scrapbook, 1916-1926, 1 oversize volume (Box 4)
      - Yearbooks, 1980, 1986, 1988-1992 (Box 4)
  - Activities
    - Bicentennial Celebration, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Birthday Luncheons (Box 4)
    - Constitutional Week, 1981, 1986, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Photographs (Box 4)
    (with notes on miscellaneous activities)
  - Financial records, 1982-1990, 4 folders (Box 4)
- Elizabeth Cass Chapter, 1942-1990
  - Minutes, 1942-1983
    - 1942-1955, 2 volumes (Box 5)
    - 1963-1983, 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Applications, 1 oversize volume (Box 5)
  - Administration
    - By-Laws, 1975, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Chartering, 1942 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 5)
    - Merger approval, 1990 (Box 5)
    - National and State remittance forms, 1983-1990 (Box 5)
    - Treasurer's reports, 1986-1990 (Box 5)
    - Yearbooks, 1944-1990 (Box 5)
  - Clippings (Box 5)
  - Genealogy (Box 5)
  - Photograph, Elizabeth Cass portrait (Box 5)
- Fort Pontchartrain-Elizabeth Cass Chapter, 1990
  (chapters merged in 1990)
  - Minutes, 1993-2001 (Box 5)
  - Applications (Box 5)
  - Administration
    - Awards (Box 5)
    - By-Laws, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Membership (Box 5)
    - Public Relations (Box 5)
    - Regent's Report (Box 5)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1996-2001 (Box 5)
    - Yearbooks, 1992-2001 (Box 5)